Well, let's celebrate our victory!
（トナリ）では我々の勝利を祝して
Cheers!
かんぱーい！
（一同）かんぱーい！
The battle with the Nokkers
（観察者）ノッカーとの戦いは
brought about a change in Fushi's
relationship with Tonari and the others.
フシとトナリたちとの関係に
変化をもたらした
Hey, don't you have any
dreams for the future?
（ミァ）
ねえ あなたは将来の夢はないの？
Dreams?
Yeah. Things you want to do.
（フシ）夢？
そう 自分がやりたいこと
I want to be able to defeat the
Nokkers by myself, I guess.
ん… １人でノッカーを
倒せるようになりたいかな
Fushi promises Tonari that he'll win the
tournament so that they can leave the island.
（観察者）島からの脱出のため
優勝すると⸺
フシはトナリに誓う
It's been a while,
（ハヤセ）久しぶりですね
Fushi.
フシ
Poor little March, huh?
マーチ…
かわいそうな少女でしたね
With her dreams and hopes
夢も希望も…
being cut short.
断ち切られて
ハッ
But awaiting Fushi in the
final tournament was Hayase,
（観察者）だが決勝戦で
フシを待ち受けていたのは
who'd made her way from Yanome.
ヤノメから やってきた
ハヤセだった
Why are you here?
（フシ）何をしに来た？
死にに来たのか？
Did you come to die?
What's your purpose here?
何のために ここに？
Well?
どうです その女の乗り心地は？
How does it feel controlling that woman?
（フシ）え？
She's so light and soft
and nimble, isn't she?
（ハヤセ）軽くて…
柔らかくて…
よく動くでしょう？
She's my gift to you.
私からの贈り物です
（フシ）あ…
You killed Parona?
あんたが…
パロナを殺したのか？
Isn't that what I just said?
今 そう言いましたが？
I'll kill you!
殺してやる！
Freedom is to never be captured by anyone.
（観察者）自由とは何物にも
捕らわれぬことである
Is it wrong to be captured?
捕らわれることは悪か？
No, it is a stepping stone toward evolution.
いや 進化への足がかりである
♪～
～♪
（歓声）
No...
そんな！
あいつが負けるなんて！
There's no way he'd lose!
Does this mean we can't leave anymore?
（ウーパ）
私たち もう外へ行けないの？
（フシ）ああ…
This is the worst.
サイテーだ
The Defeated
And thus ends an intense battle!
（実況の男）
激しい戦いの決着がつきました！
Please give a comment as the
winner of the tournament—
大会優勝者として
いや 新しい島長として
the new leader of the island!
まずは ひと言お願いします
（観客のざわめき）
My Fushi has been in your care.
私のフシが
ここで世話になりました
"My"?
私の？
I haven't heard anything about this.
何も聞いてないぞ あたしは…
I come from Yanome. My name is Hayase.
（ハヤセ）
私はヤノメから来たハヤセです
I apologize for allowing myself the
liberty of joining the competition.
誠に勝手ながら
この大会に参加いたしました
There's something that I'd like
the people of Jananda to hear.
というのも ジャナンダの民に
聞き入れてもらいたいことが
あるからです
I propose that we all, together,
protect this immortal boy, this peculiar being.
不死身の少年
この怪奇なる存在を
みんなで守りませんか？
え？
Five years ago, I found him in a feral state.
（ハヤセ）５年ほど前
まるで野獣のような彼を
私は見つけました
I took care of this boy, who couldn't
even speak, for half a year.
言葉も知らぬ彼を
半年間 保護したのですが
Perhaps because he wasn't
fully matured, he ran away.
人の精神が
芽生えきっていなかったためか
逃げ出してしまったのです
I searched desperately for him.
私は彼を必死に捜しました
I followed rumors across
the lands of this monster,
そして各地で ささやかれる
怪物のウワサをたどり
and finally, I arrived here.
ようやく ここへ行き着いたのです
She's talking out of her ass.
脚色してるねえ
It's nothing short of a miracle
that I met him again.
（ハヤセ）彼との再会
それは まさに奇跡…
Hey!
（ウーロイ）おい！
He's only here because you made
us bring him here, isn't he?!
その人が ここにいるのは
お前が俺らに
運ばせたからだろう！
No.
（ハヤセ）いいえ
あなたたちが彼を運んだのは
You brought him here by
the will of the heavens.
天の導きによるものです
What?!
（ウーロイ）はあ？
The heavens have been seeking a strong,
あなたたちのような
強くて勇ましい民を
valorous people such as yourselves.
天は求めていました
And he needs you, too.
そして彼にとっても必要なのです
That mountain of stone that
attacked the town yesterday...
昨日 この街を襲った岩山
Some of you may know that it was
he who was the first to fight it.
あのとき 真っ先に
立ち向かったのが彼だったことを
知っている方もいるでしょう
And that there were several courageous
people who fought alongside him.
さらに彼と共に戦ってくれた
勇敢な民がいたことも
I don't know what that stone creature was,
あの岩山が何かは分かりませんが
but either way, he will
need people to aid him.
いずれにせよ
彼には協力者が必要です
He's a being of unmatched abilities.
彼は類い稀(まれ)なる能力を持った
存在であり
He's the only one who can change your fate.
あなた方の運命を変えられる
唯一の存在なのです
Is he a savior from the heavens?
（観客）つまり… 天の救いか
Our... Our wishes are finally
going to be granted!
（観客）我々は…
我々は ついに報われるのか！
As his discoverer, I have the
responsibility to oversee him.
（ハヤセ）
彼を見つけた最初の人間として
管理する責任が私には あります
People of Jananda, chosen by the heavens,
天に選ばれしジャナンダの民よ
please join me in creating a defensive
army, and fight alongside me.
どうか私と守護団を結成し
共に戦ってくれませんか？
Excellent!
（観客）すばらしい！
（歓声）
I'm in!
（観客）おお やるぞ！
To hell with that!
（歓声）
（観客）ふざけるな！
その悪魔を崇拝しろってのか
You want us to worship that demon?!
You aren't from Jananda, are you?
（観客）お前 ジャナンダの
人間じゃねえだろ！
Same with the immortal there, too!
（歓声）そこの不死身も そうだ！
The choice is yours.
選択の権利は あなた方にある
I'm not interested in
ruling over this island.
私は この島を
支配したいわけではありません
I intend to give away the
rights that I've won.
優勝して得た権利は譲るつもりです
To a citizen of Jananda.
ジャナンダの民の…
え！
To the one named Tonari.
トナリという方に
Tonari?!
（観客）トナリだと？
誰だ そいつは！
（大歓声）
Who is that?
I've heard that name before.
（観客）その名前 聞いたぞ
確かスカイフィッシュの船だ
On Skyfish's ship, I think.
Let's run.
逃げよう
Yeah.
うん
If you're still not satisfied, please make
a decision based on the rules of this land.
それでも気にくわないのであれば
ここの やり方で
次の一手を決めてください
I won't interfere.
私は一切 干渉しません
Kill Tonari!
（観客）トナリを殺せ！
（観客）俺にやらせろ
（大歓声）
（観客）ヤツは どこだ？
ここにいるのか？
Is she here?
This tournament's invalid!
（大歓声）
（観客）この大会は無効だ
Start the next one already!
（観客）次の大会 始めようぜ
This is all kinds of bad.
いろいろマズい
We should have kept an eye on that woman.
あの女をマークしとくべきだったよ
What do we do now?
これから どうするの？
To those who follow me, I will guarantee
a life of abundance, free from hunger.
（ハヤセ）
私に賛同する者には富を分配し
飢えずに満たされた生活を
保障します
You won't need to work.
働かなくていい
You would need only to hear
what I say and convey it.
私の声に耳を傾け
伝えるだけでいい
I shall serve this land...
私は この島に奉仕する
The holy island of Jananda!
聖地ジャナンダへ！
（観客たち）うおおおー！
（大歓声）
（扉が開く音）
（扉が閉じる音）
（足音）
（フシ）ハァ… 情けない
Pathetic.
What's wrong? Whining already?
（酒爺(さけじい)）どうした？　もう弱音か
It hasn't even been six months
since you left on your journey.
（シン）旅に出て
まだ半年も たってないだろう？
It feels really long.
（フシ）すごく長く感じるよ
You're going to live for an eternity.
How will you ever manage
（リーン）そんなことじゃ
これから先ずっと生きていくなんて
とても できないわ
if you keep thinking that way?
I guess I just have to get used to it.
慣れればいいのか？
Including the fact that Parona's dead.
パロナが死んだってことにも？
I wonder if I'd be able to accept
it if I were to end one day.
自分にも終わりが来れば
そんなもんだって思えるのかな
I might be immortal, but I
haven't accomplished anything.
でもオレは不死身ってだけで
何もできてない
What do you think you've got March for?
何のためにマーチがいるんだ？
Yeah. And Gugu.
そうよ グーグーも
It's not that they're with me.
（フシ）いるのとは違う
It's just that I wish they were.
いてほしいと思っているだけ
No, they are.
（シン）いや いるね
You can become anything.
お前は何にだって なれる
いくらでも やり直せる
You can start over as much as you'd like.
That's what makes you who you are.
それができるのが お前なんだ
Right...
そうだ… そうなんだ
That's right.
I'm going to do it for the
people who can't start over.
やり直せない人のために
オレは やるんだ
And I'm going to save Pioran
and leave the island.
それで…
ピオランを助けて 島を出て
And in order to do that...
そのためには…
Looks like it's time to have fun.
（ハヤセ）お楽しみの時間ですね
What are you going to do with that woman?
その人をどうするんだ？
Are you going to kill her?
殺しちゃうの？
（フシ）ハッ
（イスがずれる音）
Wh-What are you doing?!
な… 何するんだ！
Stop!
やめ…
Help! Everyone!
助けて みんな
うう…
I can't move...
力が… 入らない
Poor thing.
（ハヤセ）かわいそうに
You're completely helpless.
されるがままですね
（ハヤセの荒い息）
Soon...
もうすぐ… もうすぐです
Soon.
Immortal, where are you?
不死身！　どこだ？
Immortal!
不死身 目を覚ませ！
Wake up!
ハッ！
ハァ… ハァ…
Immortal!
（トナリ）不死身 どこだ！
助けに来たぞ
Where are you?
We're here to help you!
"My Fushi," my ass.
何が“私のフシ”だ あのブスめ
That ugly pig!
（フシの荒い息）
（フシ）ハァ… ハァ…
Now of all times...
（ハヤセ）こんなときに…
It seems the drug hasn't worn off yet.
薬は まだ効いているようですね
（リガードの鳴き声）
Tonari!
（ミァ）あ！
（ミァ）トナリ！
（トナリ）ん？
That room!
（ミァ）あの部屋よ！
Hurry!
（トナリ）急ごう！
Halt!
（従者Ａ）待て！
（従者Ｂ）お前ら！
All of you!
Ligard!
リガード！
（リガードの鳴き声）
（従者Ａ）ううっ
（従者Ａ）ぐはっ
（従者Ｂ）ああ…
（従者Ｂ）うっ
Go!
（トナリ）それ！
Fujimi!
不死身！　あ…
He's gone.
Did we get the wrong room?
（ミァ）いない？
（ウーロイ）部屋 間違えたか？
Is something the matter?
（ハヤセ）どうかしましたか？
ハッ
Where's the immortal?
不死身は どこへ？
Go deep underground, to the sanctuary.
（ハヤセ）地下深くにある
聖別された部屋へ行くのです
But there, no one can touch him.
しかし そこでは
誰も彼に触ることはできない
（一同）あ…
Captain Skyfish?
（トナリ）スカイフィッシュ船長
Hey, Tonari.
（船長）よう トナリ
こんな所で どうした？
What are you doing here?
Tell me what the island leader thinks.
島長の望み 聞こうじゃないか
We're leaving this place.
あたしらは ここを出ていきます
不死身とピオランと一緒に！
With the immortal and Pioran.
Leaving?
出ていくって
船は どうやって調達する？
How will you find a ship?
You don't know?
知らないんですか？
The immortal can make a ship bigger
than the Skyfish in just five seconds.
不死身ならスカイフィッシュ号より
大きな船を
５秒で造れちゃうんスよ
ええ？
Let's go.
行こう
あっ
That's our fortune that
you're trying to steal.
（ハヤセ）我々の財産を盗もうとは
I can't let this go unpunished.
許しがたいですね
（一同）あっ
If you don't mend your ways,
I'll have to kill you.
改心しなければ
あなた方を殺さねばなりません
What a scary lady.
お姉さん こわっ
You have no intention of
giving him to us, do you?
（サンデル）
渡さないつもりなんですね
不死身さんを
When did he become your immortal?
いつから お前の不死身に
なったんだよ！
Oopa, blow darts!
ハッ ウーパ 吹き矢！
Oopa!
（一同）ああ…
（トナリ）ウーパ！
Captain Skyfish!
スカイフィッシュ船長！
What are you doing?
何をするんですか！
I say this for your own good.
悪いことは言わん 謝っておけ
Apologize.
Or else they'll kill you.
でないと殺されるぞ
（リガードの鳴き声）
Ligard!
リガード！
（一同）ああ！
I'll give you ten seconds.
10秒あげます
Decide whether you'll stop resisting
and go home, or if you'll die here.
おとなしく家に帰るか
ここで死ぬか 決めなさい
Ten...
10 ９…
Nine...
Tonari...
Eight...
（ミァ）トナリ…
（ウーロイ）覚悟はできてるぜ
I'm always prepared.
Seven...
Six...
（ハヤセ）６ ５…
Five...
Four...
４ ３…
Three...
Two...
２ １…
One.
Immortal!
（ウーロイたち）あっ
（トナリ）不死身！
Hayase-sama!
（従者たち）ああ…
（従者）ハヤセ様！
Don't move!
（フシ）動くな！
（従者たち）うう…
I'll kill her.
こいつを殺す
I'm serious. I'll really kill her.
本気だ 本当に殺すぞ！
I thought I'd taken you away.
さっき運んだはずですが
どうやって ここへ？
How did you get here?
That was just an empty husk.
あれは ただの抜け殻だ
（フシ）ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
うっ
I'm impressed.
やりますね
You're going to listen to me.
（フシ）オレの話を聞いてもらう
I get that you want to do something with me.
あんたが俺を
どうにかしたいのは分かった
Fine. I'll let you.
だったら そうさせてやる
Let the others leave in
exchange for me staying here.
オレが ここに残る代わりに
みんなを船で
乗せていってやってくれ
Immortal!
不死身！
The new leader will be
leaving this prison island.
（船長）新たな島長は
この監獄島を出ていくそうだ
We will carry this out under the guard of
the people of Yanome, on the Skyfish.
ヤノメの方々の護衛のもと
わが船スカイフィッシュ号で
これを実現させる
And at the leader's discretion,
そして今回 島長の計らいで
we will take requests for any
who would like to leave with us.
共に出ていきたい者を
募ることにした
Take me!
（男性）俺を乗せてくれ！
（ざわめき）
Please, take us!
（女性）お願い 私たちを！
Me, too!
（ざわめき）
（男性）俺もだ！
Silence! Silence!
（船長）静まれ 静まれ！
We can only take up to 700 people.
船に乗れるのは最大で700人だ
The leader will choose who they will be.
その選別は島長にしてもらう
Now, choose.
さあ 選ぶんだ
誰を連れていくか
Who are you taking?
I-I'm taking with me...
あ… あたしと一緒に行くのは…
several of my acquaintances and Pioran.
あたしの知り合い数人とピオラン
And the children.
それと子供たち ７歳以下の…
Seven and under.
Just kids?!
（男性）子供だけだと？
（どよめき）
Why seven and under?!
（男性）なんで７歳以下なんだよ！
You aren't taking us?!
（男性）俺たちは無理なのかよ？
This is bullshit!
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
（怒号）
Children deserve it!
与えられるべきなんだ 子供は！
They deserve the chance to
choose their own fates!
自分で自分の運命を
選ぶチャンスを！
For that, they need to leave this island!
そのためには
ここから出なきゃならないんだ！
Understood?
分かったな 話は以上だ
That's all from us.
If you're interested, come forth.
（従者）希望者は前に出ろ
整列するんだ
Form a line.
Go on, now.
（母）さあ 行きなさい
（子供たち）あ…
Please take care of my baby.
（母）私の赤ちゃん よろしくね
（女の子）うん…
I think I'm seven.
（島民）俺は たぶん７歳だ
だから乗せてくれよ
So please, take me.
Then I'm five.
（従者）じゃあ 俺は５歳だ
You two are staying here.
（母）あんたたちは… ここよ
I don't want to!
（ナンドの弟）ヤダよ 俺！
No. You have to go.
（ナンド）ダメだ 行くんだ
No!
（ナンドの弟）イヤだ
兄ちゃんと一緒にいる！
I want to stay with you, Brother!
Nando.
（トナリ）ナンド
Get on the ship.
あんたも船に乗って
But...
しかし…
It's fine.
（トナリ）いいんだ
不死身の代わりに私が約束を守る
I'll carry out the immortal's promise.
Later, Immortal.
じゃあな 不死身
Is this really it?
本当に もう お別れなの？
Yeah.
ああ
Fushi.
（ピオラン）フシ
I'll be waiting for you at the port in Zedan.
ゼダンの港で待っとるぞ
Yeah.
うん
I suspect you'll be dead of old
age before you're reunited.
再会する前に
きっと老衰で死んでいると
思いますよ
（ピオラン）う…
What are you—
な… 何をする！
（トナリたち）うう…
Take them.
（ハヤセ）運べ
（フシがもがく声）
Yes, ma'am.
（従者たち）はっ
Don't worry.
（フシがもがく声）
安心してください
きちんと送り届けますから
We'll take them across.
Don't you dare hurt them!
I'll make you pay if you do!
みんなを傷つけたら
許さないからな
（フシがすごむ声）
Now, we should go, too.
さあ 私たちも行きましょう
ううっ う…
（扉が開く音）
（落ちる音）
（トナリ）ん…
Tonari.
（班長）トナリ
（トナリ）ん… あっ
Boss...
班長
Untie me.
ほどいて
R-Right.
あ… おお
Was everyone knocked out?
（トナリ）
みんな 眠らされたのか？
No, just you kids.
（班長）いや お前らだけだ
Damn, it hasn't been five minutes.
ったく ５分も たってねえぞ
Those bastards said you'd be
asleep for two hours at least.
連中 ２時間は眠るって
ほざいてたのに
What's the deal with you, Tonari?
おい トナリ
お前だけ どうなってんだよ
I wonder why.
ん… なんでだろ？
（物音）
We're leaving.
おっ 出航だ
The time's finally come.
ついに来たな このときが
Boss...
（トナリ）班長！
（班長）ん？
Give me a hand.
あたしに協力して！
Are you sure, Tonari?
（班長）本当か トナリ？
Are you really going to go save him?
本当に あいつを助けに行くのか？
Shh!
Just let me down!
シーッ いいから早く下ろして！
What am I supposed to tell the others?
ほかの連中には何て言うんだ？
Tell them not to look for me.
“捜さないで”
That I have a tummyache,
and the bathrooms are busy.
“腹痛なのに
トイレが混んでるんだ”って
Hey! What are you doing?
（従者）あっ おい 何してる！
（班長）あっ ヤバい…
Shit.
（リガードの鳴き声）
（従者）お… わっ
うわっ うう…
Ligard!
（トナリ）リガード！
Thank goodness! You're okay!
よかった 無事だったんだね
I thought it was too late for you.
てっきり もうダメかと思ってたよ
Go to the right.
右に回れ そっちが死角だ！
There's a blind spot there.
Got it? Don't get caught!
いいか 見つかるなよ
Okay.
（トナリ）うん ありがとう 班長！
Thanks, boss.
Hey! What do you think you're doing?!
（ナンド）
おい お前 何をやってるんだ！
ええっ
Take care of the kids for me!
子供たちの面倒 よろしく！
What?!
何だと…
Keep everyone safe!
（トナリ）どうか みんなを無事に
お願いね！
Please!
All right.
わ… 分かった
H-Hey, look over there!
（従者）お… おい あれ見ろ！
We have to let Hayase-sama know.
（従者）
早くハヤセ様に知らせなければ
（従者）うむ…
（２人）ぐおお…
（船長）フンッ
No messing around on my ship.
俺の船で
勝手なマネするんじゃねえ
I made a last-minute decision
to add to my story.
（トナリ）私は急きょ
私の物語を書き足すことにした
The story of what lies in store
for an unknowable life form.
それは 得体の知れない生物の
その先を見届ける物語だ
I was relieved during the tournament.
大会のとき 私は安心した
I'll kill you!
殺してやる！
To know that there are some things
even he won't accept.
（トナリ）あいつにも
許せないことがあるんだって
That makes him seem kind of human.
それが何だか人間っぽい
And kind of like me.
そして私っぽい
I want him to be in my future.
私の未来に あいつがいてほしい
♪～
～♪
Preview
Tonari returns to the island to
help Fushi out of captivity.
（観察者）
捕らわれのフシを助けるため
再び島へ戻ったトナリ
There, they encounter the Nokkers.
そこでノッカーの出現を知る
As the city of Jananda
is attacked by monsters,
怪物に襲われたジャナンダの街
she and Fushi are met by
an unbelievable sight.
フシたちは
信じられない光景を目にする
To Continue On